<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Cloud Native &amp; Open Source: A Team Lead’s Working Journal</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Cloud Native &amp; Open Source: A Team Lead’s Working Journal</description>
    <image>
      <title>Cloud Native &amp; Open Source: A Team Lead’s Working Journal</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.7</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 16:23:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Is It Possible to Make Both Developers and Security Officers Happy? Try Snyk!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-make-developers-and-security-officers-happy-with-snyk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 16:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-make-developers-and-security-officers-happy-with-snyk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being able to work safely in cybersecurity requires knowledge, attention to detail, and a solid portfolio of reliable software.&lt;br&gt;
One of the tools I have learned about and used in recent months is Snyk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;snyk certification&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/how-make-developers-and-security-officers-happy-with-snyk/snyk-pro.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calling Snyk a “tool” isn’t quite accurate—it’s a security platform that offers a suite of tools capable of operating on any codebase, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://snyk.io/product/snyk-code/&#34;&gt;Code (SAST)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://snyk.io/product/open-source-security-management/&#34;&gt;Open Source (SCA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://snyk.io/product/container-vulnerability-management/&#34;&gt;Containers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://snyk.io/product/infrastructure-as-code-security/&#34;&gt;Infrastructure as Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://snyk.io/product/infrastructure-as-code-security/&#34;&gt;Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the amount of code produced has grown exponentially. The availability of countless open-source libraries and containers has accelerated development, but how can we be sure that all these resources are secure?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting CyberArk Conjur Follower Setup and Postgres Connectivity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/troubleshooting-conjur-follower-setup-postgres-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 11:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/troubleshooting-conjur-follower-setup-postgres-connectivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During our work with a CyberArk Conjur environment, we encountered strange behavior during the Conjur follower setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setup process on the follower would start, the seed was received, imported, and expanded, but after a few more steps, the process would hang and end with a generic &amp;ldquo;System Error.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After displaying the error message, the Conjur follower would restart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We performed troubleshooting inside the Conjur Follower pod and verified that the follower could connect to the Conjur API leader successfully, but it was unable to connect to the Postgres database and complete the initial replication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Vault Synchronizer – CASVM035E Vault Name Is Missing: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-vault-synchronizer-casvm035e-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 07:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-vault-synchronizer-casvm035e-fix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may know, one of the key components of the CyberArk Conjur architecture is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.cyberark.com/Product-Doc/OnlineHelp/AAM-DAP/Latest/en/Content/Conjur/cv_Synchronizer-lp.htm&#34;&gt;Synchronizer&lt;/a&gt;, which is required to receive secrets from the Vault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I took charge of an abandoned Synchronizer version 11.7 that had not been working for some time and also needed to be upgraded to the latest 12.7 release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing the upgrade (check &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.cyberark.com/conjur-enterprise/latest/en/content/conjur/cv_upgrade.htm?tocpath=Integrations%7CCyberArk%20Vault%20Synchronizer%7C_____11&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; for the steps), the Windows service failed to start, and the log contained the following error:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Impact 2022 World Tour – Will You Be There?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-impact-world-tour-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 19:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-impact-world-tour-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you probably know, CyberArk hosts a major annual event called Impact, which this year took place in Boston.&lt;br&gt;
In recent weeks, CyberArk has announced an exciting initiative: the CyberArk Impact World Tour, which will be hosted in several cities around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested, you can find all the details &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cyberark.com/impact-world-tour/&#34;&gt;on this page&lt;/a&gt;, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cities involved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agenda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registration form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’ll be attending the event in Milan, scheduled for October 11th, 2022.&lt;br&gt;
I’m excited for the opportunity to attend some fascinating sessions and meet interesting people in person. See you there!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur, authenticators and integrations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-authenticators-integrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 10:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-authenticators-integrations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the past few weeks, I have described what a secrets manager is and provided an overview of the architecture and system requirements of CyberArk Conjur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A secrets manager can&amp;rsquo;t do its job if it can&amp;rsquo;t communicate with those who need to request  secrets, and that&amp;rsquo;s where Conjur&amp;rsquo;s magic comes in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;authenticators&amp;rdquo; are responsible for the authentication process in Conjur and are specialized to do this in the most secure way, depending on the service.&lt;br&gt;
Here is the list of authenticators currently supported:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur: A Quick Overview of Architecture and System Requirements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-architecture-system-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 11:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-architecture-system-requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I wrote in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/why-you-need-kubernetes-secrets-manager/&#34;&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt;, CyberArk Conjur is an enterprise secrets manager.
, CyberArk Conjur is an enterprise secrets manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’ll provide an architecture overview along with the main system requirements.&lt;br&gt;
Conjur is currently available in two versions: Enterprise and open source (known as OSS).&lt;br&gt;
A &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; version will be available soon, offered as a SaaS solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post focuses on the Enterprise version, which is similar but not identical to the OSS version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur - why you (probably) need an enterprise secrets manager</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-you-need-kubernetes-secrets-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 16:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-you-need-kubernetes-secrets-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Security is always a complex topic to address, as an error or omission in processes can lead to serious economic or reputational damage for a company.&lt;br&gt;
When we talk about &amp;ldquo;secrets,&amp;rdquo; consider the following examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usernames&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database passwords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSL certificates and keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud credentials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply reading through this list helps to explain why this topic needs to be considered and handled carefully.&lt;br&gt;
Some common bad practices or risks include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve started a new journey as DevSecOps Team Leader</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-job-devsecops-teamleader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-job-devsecops-teamleader/</guid>
      <description>A new beginning</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
