<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud Native &amp; Open Source: A Team Lead’s Working Journal</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cloud Native &amp; Open Source: A Team Lead’s Working Journal</description>
    <image>
      <title>Cloud Native &amp; Open Source: A Team Lead’s Working Journal</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.7</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 11:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Privacy Notice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last updated: June 04, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-we-are&#34;&gt;Who We Are&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.msbiro.net&#34;&gt;www.msbiro.net&lt;/a&gt; is a personal blog operated by Matteo Bisi.&lt;br&gt;
For any privacy-related inquiries, you can contact me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mbisi@msbiro.net&#34;&gt;mbisi@msbiro.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-information-we-collect&#34;&gt;What Information We Collect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website itself does not collect personal data from visitors.&lt;br&gt;
However, when you visit this site, certain technical information (such as your IP address, browser type, and device information)&lt;br&gt;
is automatically collected and processed by our hosting provider, Cloudflare, to deliver the website securely and efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me - Matteo Bisi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>Who am I?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing Kubernetes 1.33 Pods: The Impact of User Namespace Isolation and hostUsers: false</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubernetes-133-user-namespace-isolation-security-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 09:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubernetes-133-user-namespace-isolation-security-matters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes 1.33 was released on April 23, 2025, and, as usual, introduces a host of fixes and new features. Be sure to check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/blog/2025/04/23/kubernetes-v1-33-release/&#34;&gt;the release notes&lt;/a&gt;; I assure you, you won’t be disappointed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Team Leader of a DevSecOps group, I tend to focus on security features. In this article, I want to highlight the new pod support for user namespaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feature isn’t entirely new—it was first introduced as an Alpha feature (&lt;code&gt;UserNamespacesSupport&lt;/code&gt;) in Kubernetes 1.28. However, as of version 1.33, it is enabled by default, and there’s no longer any need to set a Kubernetes feature flag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Manual to GitOps: Simplifying Grafana Dashboard Configuration with Git Sync</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/grafana-dashboard-configuration-with-gitops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 11:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/grafana-dashboard-configuration-with-gitops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting with version 12, Grafana introduces the ability to configure dashboards using a GitOps approach through an experimental feature called &lt;strong&gt;Git Sync&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a particularly interesting capability that can help manage dashboards in large and complex environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git Sync is available as an experimental feature in both Grafana OSS and Enterprise editions. Activation can also be requested for the Cloud version (currently available as a private preview).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the relevant documentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://grafana.com/docs/grafana/latest/observability-as-code/provision-resources/intro-git-sync/&#34;&gt;in this page&lt;/a&gt;, and below I am including a demo video.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSF - Open Source Project Security Baseline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/openssf-opensource-project-security-baseline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/openssf-opensource-project-security-baseline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to share with you a new initiative by OpenSSF called the Open Source Project Security Baseline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;openssf logo&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/openssf-opensource-project-security-baseline/openssf_logo.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TL;DR: This initiative consists of a series of checks that project maintainers must have in place in their software repositories to demonstrate a strong security posture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The baseline is divided into three well defined levels. I find this to be an interesting and practical initiative, easy to apply for improving and certifying a project&amp;rsquo;s security level.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KubeCon EU 2025 London</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubecon-2025-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 09:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubecon-2025-london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The countdown to KubeCon EU (London) has begun, and I couldn’t be more thrilled to announce that, for the third year in a row, I’ll have the incredible privilege of attending!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;kubecon london EU&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/kubecon-2025-london/kubecon-london-logo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year is extra special because, for the second time, I’ll be managing a booth alongside my amazing colleagues.&lt;br&gt;
Why? Because &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reevo.it/en/&#34;&gt;ReeVo&lt;/a&gt;, the company that SIGHUP has now joined, will proudly be a sponsor of this major event!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolving &#39;Operation Not Permitted&#39; for CyberArk Conjur Cloud CLI on macOS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/resolving-operation-not-permitted-cyberark-conjur-cloud-cli-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 16:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/resolving-operation-not-permitted-cyberark-conjur-cloud-cli-macos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a consultant, it&amp;rsquo;s always a pleasure to explore new tools, and since the end of 2024, we have been experimenting with CyberArk&amp;rsquo;s SaaS offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first component we started working with is Conjur Cloud, the SaaS version of Conjur Enterprise, which we are already very familiar with.
Conjur Cloud features an impressive UI that allows users to configure and manage most settings seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Conjur Enterprise, it also has its own dedicated CLI, available for download on the CyberArk Marketplace. After installing the Conjur Cloud CLI on macOS 15.2, I encountered the following error when attempting to execute it:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>macOS, Podman Desktop and the Podman Machine: Pay Close Attention to the Podman Version</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/podman-desktop-and-podman-machine-on-macos-pay-attention-to-podman-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/podman-desktop-and-podman-machine-on-macos-pay-attention-to-podman-version/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.podman.io/&#34;&gt;Podman&lt;/a&gt; as the standard tool requested by clients for running local containers outside of a Kubernetes environment, I decided to start the year by installing Podman Desktop on my company MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podman Desktop features a user interface (UI) similar to Docker Desktop, making it easier to manage containers and images.&lt;br&gt;
It also includes plugin management to extend its functionality, such as deploying containers on Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After installing Podman Desktop version 1.15.0, I proceeded with the setup but encountered issues with the Podman machine (the virtual machine dedicated to running containers) which failed to start. There were no errors; it just hung during startup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confirmed as KubeWeekly Editor: Giving Back to the Cloud-Native Community in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/confirmed-as-kubeweekly-editor-2025-giving-back-to-cloud-native-community-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 08:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/confirmed-as-kubeweekly-editor-2025-giving-back-to-cloud-native-community-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the pleasures of working with open-source software (OSS) and community-driven initiatives is the endless opportunities they offer.&lt;br&gt;
If you ever find yourself with “not enough” to do at work (yes, that’s ironic!), there’s always an easy way to take on something extra and meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributing back to the community you’re part of is a wonderful way to express gratitude. &lt;strong&gt;After all, how could anyone be luckier than to give back to something they love?&lt;/strong&gt; 😊&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KCD Italy Will Return in 2025 with a New Name</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kcd-italy-return-2025-as-cloud-native-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 18:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kcd-italy-return-2025-as-cloud-native-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the organizers of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/cloudnativedaysitaly/posts/?feedView=all&#34;&gt;KCD Italy announced&lt;/a&gt; that the conference will return in 2025, once again in Bologna, in June!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For various organizational reasons, the conference will be rebranded as Cloud Native Days Italy, &lt;strong&gt;but the quality will remain just as high.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, no further details are available. Start marking your calendar—see you in Bologna!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Conference – BSides Galway, February 22nd, 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bsides-galway-february-22-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 13:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bsides-galway-february-22-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a couple of years since I moved to Galway, and I’m still absolutely thrilled with my decision!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months, I’ve had the chance to meet some awesome people at a local security meetup called &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/burbsecgalway&#34;&gt;BurbSec&lt;/a&gt;. It was a fantastic experience—sharing ideas, meeting new faces, and of course, enjoying a few beers! ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, some of these folks are organizing a security conference called BSIDES Galway, happening on February 22nd, 2025!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur 13.4 – The Evolution Continues</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-134-evolution-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 07:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-134-evolution-continues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, a new release of Conjur Enterprise was launched—now at version 13.4, bringing exciting new features to the product!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my top three favorites, though there are many more updates, which you can find &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.cyberark.com/conjur-enterprise/13.4/en/content/enterprise/whatsnew.htm?TocPath=Get%20started%7C_____2&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sync of empty safes from Vault: This is essential for managing policy creation through automation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamic application configuration: It is now possible to modify various Conjur configuration parameters that previously had to be set when creating the container. Now, they are all included in the usual conjur.yml.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extended ESO support: The External Secrets Operator can now use regex in findByName and findByTags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As has been the case for several releases, I’d like to reiterate that CyberArk’s development of Conjur is moving quickly, and with each release, the product becomes more and more complete.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>cryptsetup: How to Protect Entire Disks or USB Keys – Notes on technical_notebook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cryptsetup-protect-entire-disk-or-usb-key-notes-technical-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 18:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cryptsetup-protect-entire-disk-or-usb-key-notes-technical-notebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using an encrypted USB drive for several years, which unlocks with biometric access.&lt;br&gt;
Recently, I started wondering how to achieve the same level of protection with other disks or USB keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is cryptsetup, a utility included in most Linux distributions.&lt;br&gt;
I’ve done some tests and documented how to use it in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/matteobisi/technical_notebook&#34;&gt;repository I’ve named technical_notebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll use technical_notebook as a personal notebook—it will contain commands, concepts, and useful links.&lt;br&gt;
The purpose of the repo is to help me remember these details, keep them easily accessible, and perhaps assist others who have similar needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KubeCon 2024: Why Attending a Conference Is Important and Some Useful Resources</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubecon-eu-2024-why-attending-a-conference-is-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 05:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubecon-eu-2024-why-attending-a-conference-is-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, I had the pleasure of attending KubeCon 2024 EU in Paris.
I must begin by &lt;strong&gt;thanking &lt;a href=&#34;https://sighup.io/&#34;&gt;SIGHUP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for giving me the opportunity to participate in my second consecutive KubeCon, &lt;strong&gt;THANK YOU!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to write this post to encourage those who have never attended a large-scale event to give it a try!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-this-case-size-matters&#34;&gt;In this case, size matters!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re involved in the cloud native world as a client, developer, consultant, or major vendor you can’t miss it!&lt;br&gt;
Colleagues, clients, partners, competitors, maintainers of small projects, volunteer committees, and big corporations—they’re all there!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur 13.2 Released: Another Step in the Right Direction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-132-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-132-released/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One week ago, CyberArk released another update for Conjur Enterprise, which has now reached version 13.2—definitely another step in the right direction!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release includes the usual bug fixes, expands Conjur’s integrations (for example, OpenShift 4.14 is now supported), and, most importantly, adds two exciting new features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CyberArk Vault Synchronizer high availability support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced Conjur support for the Container Storage Interface (CSI) driver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synchronizer high availability enhances Conjur’s disaster recovery (DR) strategy.&lt;br&gt;
It is now possible to set up a &amp;ldquo;passive&amp;rdquo; Synchronizer in a DR site that is aware of the status of the primary Synchronizer and can take over in case of a failure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KubeWeekly – Get Weekly Kubernetes News in Your Inbox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubeweekly-k8s-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubeweekly-k8s-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there! As I mentioned before, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/the-value-of-community-contributions-exploring-cncf-openssf/&#34;&gt;I’ve always been&lt;/a&gt; a community person, and I’ve found a new way to contribute:&lt;br&gt;
during the first half of 2024, I’ll be one of the editors helping to curate content for KubeWeekly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KubeWeekly is a newsletter that delivers a curated selection of news, tweets, articles, and videos about Kubernetes and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://landscape.cncf.io/&#34;&gt;CNCF landscape&lt;/a&gt; straight to your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to see what we’re working on or join the mailing list, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cncf.io/kubeweekly/&#34;&gt;please check out this page&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KCD 2024 Italy Announced – Bologna, 20 June 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kcd-italy-2024-bologna/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 11:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kcd-italy-2024-bologna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there! Just a quick post to share that &lt;a href=&#34;https://kcd.pizza/&#34;&gt;KCD Italy&lt;/a&gt; has been announced and will take place in Bologna on 20 June 2024!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;kcd call for paper&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/kcd-italy-2024-bologna/kcd-cfp.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not directly involved in organizing this event, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sighup.io/&#34;&gt;but my company is&lt;/a&gt;, so I’m publishing this post to help spread the word!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CFP (Call for Proposals) is open and available at this link. English sessions are welcome!&lt;br&gt;
We are also still looking for new sponsors. If you’re interested, please contact one of the organizers or reach out to me, and I’ll put you in touch with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur 13.1 Released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-131-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 08:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-131-released/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, CyberArk released a new and interesting version of Conjur: 13.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This point release is really interesting because it brings important under-the-hood updates that aim to increase the resiliency of followers.&lt;br&gt;
If you want to read more about this release, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.sighup.io/cyberark-conjur-13-1-has-been-relased-with-interesting-updates-under-the-hood/&#34;&gt;check out the article&lt;/a&gt; I wrote on the SIGHUP blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KubeCon EU 2024 Paris – Exploring the Kubetrain Initiative</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubecon-eu-2024-paris-kubetrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubecon-eu-2024-paris-kubetrain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, KubeCon NA in Chicago came to a close, so now we can start looking forward to KubeCon EU 2024,&lt;br&gt;
which will take place in Paris from March 19th to 22nd, 2024 😊.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Paris, &lt;a href=&#34;https://events.linuxfoundation.org/kubecon-cloudnativecon-europe/register/&#34;&gt;early bird registrations&lt;/a&gt; are open until November 28th, and it’s still possible to &lt;a href=&#34;https://events.linuxfoundation.org/kubecon-cloudnativecon-europe/program/cfp/&#34;&gt;submit proposals for the call for papers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to share an interesting initiative called Kubetrain, which aims to help attendees reach Paris in a more environmentally sustainable way by choosing trains over planes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Community Contributions: Exploring CNCF and OpenSSF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-value-of-community-contributions-exploring-cncf-openssf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 16:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-value-of-community-contributions-exploring-cncf-openssf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll start with a premise for those who may not already be familiar: the open-source software ecosystem often revolves around foundations, with the most famous probably being the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/&#34;&gt;Linux Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the cloud-native domain, the reference foundation is the Cloud Native Computing Foundation, commonly known as CNCF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cncf.io/about/who-we-are/&#34;&gt;CNCF&lt;/a&gt; is a foundation created by the Linux Foundation in 2015, specifically to manage projects in the cloud-native domain. In simple terms, it can be defined as a third-party, vendor-neutral entity that oversees the development and activities related to major projects involving containerized technologies like Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur 13 has been released.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/conjur-13-is-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 18:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/conjur-13-is-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the previous days, CyberArk has released version 13.0 of Conjur Enterprise.&lt;br&gt;
What’s new? Who should consider upgrading, and why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve published an &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.sighup.io/cyberark-conjur-13-0-has-been-released-whats-new/&#34;&gt;article on these topics here&lt;/a&gt; on the SIGHUP blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolving Podman Log Rotation Issues in CyberArk Conjur Container 12.9 Deployments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/resolving-podman-log-rotation-issue-conjur-enterprise-129/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 17:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/resolving-podman-log-rotation-issue-conjur-enterprise-129/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CyberArk Conjur is released as an appliance and distributed as container images to enable fast, error-free setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supported container runtimes include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker 20.10 or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mirantis Container Runtime 20.10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podman 3.x, 4.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working with multiple Conjur environments in our labs and at customer sites, we noticed that log rotation (for Conjur, Nginx, cluster, etc.) did not function correctly on Podman, although it worked as expected on Docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some investigation with the excellent CyberArk support team, we identified the solution:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SIGHUP Secure Containers: how do you choose the oci base image for your workload?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sighup-secure-container-how-choose-base-image-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 12:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sighup-secure-container-how-choose-base-image-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe it’s important to start with a premise:&lt;br&gt;
In this article, I’ll talk about a product/service built and offered by my current employer, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sighup.io&#34;&gt;SIGHUP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;SIGHUP SSC logo&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/sighup-secure-container-how-choose-base-image-security/sighup-ssc.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one from my company has asked me to publish this blog post here; these are my honest opinions about &lt;a href=&#34;https://sighup.io/secure-containers/&#34;&gt;Secure Containers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secure Containers is a paid service built by SIGHUP that provides secure, hardened, and updated &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.com/article/21/8/container-image&#34;&gt;container base images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
Developers working with containers and images now enjoy several advantages compared to the past, such as standardization, automation, and faster release times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Is It Possible to Make Both Developers and Security Officers Happy? Try Snyk!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-make-developers-and-security-officers-happy-with-snyk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 16:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-make-developers-and-security-officers-happy-with-snyk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being able to work safely in cybersecurity requires knowledge, attention to detail, and a solid portfolio of reliable software.&lt;br&gt;
One of the tools I have learned about and used in recent months is Snyk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;snyk certification&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/how-make-developers-and-security-officers-happy-with-snyk/snyk-pro.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calling Snyk a “tool” isn’t quite accurate—it’s a security platform that offers a suite of tools capable of operating on any codebase, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://snyk.io/product/snyk-code/&#34;&gt;Code (SAST)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://snyk.io/product/open-source-security-management/&#34;&gt;Open Source (SCA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://snyk.io/product/container-vulnerability-management/&#34;&gt;Containers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://snyk.io/product/infrastructure-as-code-security/&#34;&gt;Infrastructure as Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://snyk.io/product/infrastructure-as-code-security/&#34;&gt;Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the amount of code produced has grown exponentially. The availability of countless open-source libraries and containers has accelerated development, but how can we be sure that all these resources are secure?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting CyberArk Conjur Follower Setup and Postgres Connectivity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/troubleshooting-conjur-follower-setup-postgres-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 11:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/troubleshooting-conjur-follower-setup-postgres-connectivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During our work with a CyberArk Conjur environment, we encountered strange behavior during the Conjur follower setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setup process on the follower would start, the seed was received, imported, and expanded, but after a few more steps, the process would hang and end with a generic &amp;ldquo;System Error.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After displaying the error message, the Conjur follower would restart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We performed troubleshooting inside the Conjur Follower pod and verified that the follower could connect to the Conjur API leader successfully, but it was unable to connect to the Postgres database and complete the initial replication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Vault Synchronizer – CASVM035E Vault Name Is Missing: How to Fix It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-vault-synchronizer-casvm035e-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 07:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-vault-synchronizer-casvm035e-fix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may know, one of the key components of the CyberArk Conjur architecture is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.cyberark.com/Product-Doc/OnlineHelp/AAM-DAP/Latest/en/Content/Conjur/cv_Synchronizer-lp.htm&#34;&gt;Synchronizer&lt;/a&gt;, which is required to receive secrets from the Vault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I took charge of an abandoned Synchronizer version 11.7 that had not been working for some time and also needed to be upgraded to the latest 12.7 release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing the upgrade (check &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.cyberark.com/conjur-enterprise/latest/en/content/conjur/cv_upgrade.htm?tocpath=Integrations%7CCyberArk%20Vault%20Synchronizer%7C_____11&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; for the steps), the Windows service failed to start, and the log contained the following error:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Impact 2022 World Tour – Will You Be There?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-impact-world-tour-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 19:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-impact-world-tour-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you probably know, CyberArk hosts a major annual event called Impact, which this year took place in Boston.&lt;br&gt;
In recent weeks, CyberArk has announced an exciting initiative: the CyberArk Impact World Tour, which will be hosted in several cities around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested, you can find all the details &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cyberark.com/impact-world-tour/&#34;&gt;on this page&lt;/a&gt;, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cities involved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agenda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registration form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’ll be attending the event in Milan, scheduled for October 11th, 2022.&lt;br&gt;
I’m excited for the opportunity to attend some fascinating sessions and meet interesting people in person. See you there!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur, authenticators and integrations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-authenticators-integrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 10:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-authenticators-integrations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the past few weeks, I have described what a secrets manager is and provided an overview of the architecture and system requirements of CyberArk Conjur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A secrets manager can&amp;rsquo;t do its job if it can&amp;rsquo;t communicate with those who need to request  secrets, and that&amp;rsquo;s where Conjur&amp;rsquo;s magic comes in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;authenticators&amp;rdquo; are responsible for the authentication process in Conjur and are specialized to do this in the most secure way, depending on the service.&lt;br&gt;
Here is the list of authenticators currently supported:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur: A Quick Overview of Architecture and System Requirements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-architecture-system-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 11:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-architecture-system-requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I wrote in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/why-you-need-kubernetes-secrets-manager/&#34;&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt;, CyberArk Conjur is an enterprise secrets manager.
, CyberArk Conjur is an enterprise secrets manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’ll provide an architecture overview along with the main system requirements.&lt;br&gt;
Conjur is currently available in two versions: Enterprise and open source (known as OSS).&lt;br&gt;
A &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; version will be available soon, offered as a SaaS solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post focuses on the Enterprise version, which is similar but not identical to the OSS version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur - why you (probably) need an enterprise secrets manager</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-you-need-kubernetes-secrets-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 16:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-you-need-kubernetes-secrets-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Security is always a complex topic to address, as an error or omission in processes can lead to serious economic or reputational damage for a company.&lt;br&gt;
When we talk about &amp;ldquo;secrets,&amp;rdquo; consider the following examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usernames&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database passwords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSL certificates and keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud credentials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply reading through this list helps to explain why this topic needs to be considered and handled carefully.&lt;br&gt;
Some common bad practices or risks include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve started a new journey as DevSecOps Team Leader</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-job-devsecops-teamleader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-job-devsecops-teamleader/</guid>
      <description>A new beginning</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
