<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on Cloud Native &amp; Open Source: A Team Lead’s Working Journal</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on Cloud Native &amp; Open Source: A Team Lead’s Working Journal</description>
    <image>
      <title>Cloud Native &amp; Open Source: A Team Lead’s Working Journal</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.7</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 09:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>KubeCon EU 2025 London</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubecon-2025-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 09:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubecon-2025-london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The countdown to KubeCon EU (London) has begun, and I couldn’t be more thrilled to announce that, for the third year in a row, I’ll have the incredible privilege of attending!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;kubecon london EU&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/kubecon-2025-london/kubecon-london-logo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year is extra special because, for the second time, I’ll be managing a booth alongside my amazing colleagues.&lt;br&gt;
Why? Because &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reevo.it/en/&#34;&gt;ReeVo&lt;/a&gt;, the company that SIGHUP has now joined, will proudly be a sponsor of this major event!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confirmed as KubeWeekly Editor: Giving Back to the Cloud-Native Community in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/confirmed-as-kubeweekly-editor-2025-giving-back-to-cloud-native-community-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 08:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/confirmed-as-kubeweekly-editor-2025-giving-back-to-cloud-native-community-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the pleasures of working with open-source software (OSS) and community-driven initiatives is the endless opportunities they offer.&lt;br&gt;
If you ever find yourself with “not enough” to do at work (yes, that’s ironic!), there’s always an easy way to take on something extra and meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributing back to the community you’re part of is a wonderful way to express gratitude. &lt;strong&gt;After all, how could anyone be luckier than to give back to something they love?&lt;/strong&gt; 😊&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KCD Italy Will Return in 2025 with a New Name</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kcd-italy-return-2025-as-cloud-native-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 18:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kcd-italy-return-2025-as-cloud-native-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the organizers of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/cloudnativedaysitaly/posts/?feedView=all&#34;&gt;KCD Italy announced&lt;/a&gt; that the conference will return in 2025, once again in Bologna, in June!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For various organizational reasons, the conference will be rebranded as Cloud Native Days Italy, &lt;strong&gt;but the quality will remain just as high.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, no further details are available. Start marking your calendar—see you in Bologna!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Conference – BSides Galway, February 22nd, 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bsides-galway-february-22-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 13:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bsides-galway-february-22-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a couple of years since I moved to Galway, and I’m still absolutely thrilled with my decision!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months, I’ve had the chance to meet some awesome people at a local security meetup called &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/burbsecgalway&#34;&gt;BurbSec&lt;/a&gt;. It was a fantastic experience—sharing ideas, meeting new faces, and of course, enjoying a few beers! ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, some of these folks are organizing a security conference called BSIDES Galway, happening on February 22nd, 2025!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KubeCon 2024: Why Attending a Conference Is Important and Some Useful Resources</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubecon-eu-2024-why-attending-a-conference-is-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 05:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubecon-eu-2024-why-attending-a-conference-is-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, I had the pleasure of attending KubeCon 2024 EU in Paris.
I must begin by &lt;strong&gt;thanking &lt;a href=&#34;https://sighup.io/&#34;&gt;SIGHUP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for giving me the opportunity to participate in my second consecutive KubeCon, &lt;strong&gt;THANK YOU!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to write this post to encourage those who have never attended a large-scale event to give it a try!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-this-case-size-matters&#34;&gt;In this case, size matters!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re involved in the cloud native world as a client, developer, consultant, or major vendor you can’t miss it!&lt;br&gt;
Colleagues, clients, partners, competitors, maintainers of small projects, volunteer committees, and big corporations—they’re all there!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KubeWeekly – Get Weekly Kubernetes News in Your Inbox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubeweekly-k8s-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kubeweekly-k8s-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there! As I mentioned before, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/the-value-of-community-contributions-exploring-cncf-openssf/&#34;&gt;I’ve always been&lt;/a&gt; a community person, and I’ve found a new way to contribute:&lt;br&gt;
during the first half of 2024, I’ll be one of the editors helping to curate content for KubeWeekly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KubeWeekly is a newsletter that delivers a curated selection of news, tweets, articles, and videos about Kubernetes and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://landscape.cncf.io/&#34;&gt;CNCF landscape&lt;/a&gt; straight to your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to see what we’re working on or join the mailing list, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cncf.io/kubeweekly/&#34;&gt;please check out this page&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KCD 2024 Italy Announced – Bologna, 20 June 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kcd-italy-2024-bologna/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 11:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kcd-italy-2024-bologna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there! Just a quick post to share that &lt;a href=&#34;https://kcd.pizza/&#34;&gt;KCD Italy&lt;/a&gt; has been announced and will take place in Bologna on 20 June 2024!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;kcd call for paper&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/kcd-italy-2024-bologna/kcd-cfp.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not directly involved in organizing this event, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sighup.io/&#34;&gt;but my company is&lt;/a&gt;, so I’m publishing this post to help spread the word!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CFP (Call for Proposals) is open and available at this link. English sessions are welcome!&lt;br&gt;
We are also still looking for new sponsors. If you’re interested, please contact one of the organizers or reach out to me, and I’ll put you in touch with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Community Contributions: Exploring CNCF and OpenSSF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-value-of-community-contributions-exploring-cncf-openssf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 16:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-value-of-community-contributions-exploring-cncf-openssf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll start with a premise for those who may not already be familiar: the open-source software ecosystem often revolves around foundations, with the most famous probably being the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/&#34;&gt;Linux Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the cloud-native domain, the reference foundation is the Cloud Native Computing Foundation, commonly known as CNCF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cncf.io/about/who-we-are/&#34;&gt;CNCF&lt;/a&gt; is a foundation created by the Linux Foundation in 2015, specifically to manage projects in the cloud-native domain. In simple terms, it can be defined as a third-party, vendor-neutral entity that oversees the development and activities related to major projects involving containerized technologies like Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
