<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Conjur on Cloud Native &amp; Open Source: A Team Lead’s Working Journal</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/conjur/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conjur on Cloud Native &amp; Open Source: A Team Lead’s Working Journal</description>
    <image>
      <title>Cloud Native &amp; Open Source: A Team Lead’s Working Journal</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.7</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 08:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/conjur/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur 13.1 Released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-131-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 08:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-131-released/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, CyberArk released a new and interesting version of Conjur: 13.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This point release is really interesting because it brings important under-the-hood updates that aim to increase the resiliency of followers.&lt;br&gt;
If you want to read more about this release, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.sighup.io/cyberark-conjur-13-1-has-been-relased-with-interesting-updates-under-the-hood/&#34;&gt;check out the article&lt;/a&gt; I wrote on the SIGHUP blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur 13 has been released.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/conjur-13-is-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 18:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/conjur-13-is-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the previous days, CyberArk has released version 13.0 of Conjur Enterprise.&lt;br&gt;
What’s new? Who should consider upgrading, and why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve published an &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.sighup.io/cyberark-conjur-13-0-has-been-released-whats-new/&#34;&gt;article on these topics here&lt;/a&gt; on the SIGHUP blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolving Podman Log Rotation Issues in CyberArk Conjur Container 12.9 Deployments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/resolving-podman-log-rotation-issue-conjur-enterprise-129/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 17:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/resolving-podman-log-rotation-issue-conjur-enterprise-129/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CyberArk Conjur is released as an appliance and distributed as container images to enable fast, error-free setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supported container runtimes include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker 20.10 or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mirantis Container Runtime 20.10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podman 3.x, 4.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working with multiple Conjur environments in our labs and at customer sites, we noticed that log rotation (for Conjur, Nginx, cluster, etc.) did not function correctly on Podman, although it worked as expected on Docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some investigation with the excellent CyberArk support team, we identified the solution:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting CyberArk Conjur Follower Setup and Postgres Connectivity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/troubleshooting-conjur-follower-setup-postgres-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 11:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/troubleshooting-conjur-follower-setup-postgres-connectivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During our work with a CyberArk Conjur environment, we encountered strange behavior during the Conjur follower setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setup process on the follower would start, the seed was received, imported, and expanded, but after a few more steps, the process would hang and end with a generic &amp;ldquo;System Error.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After displaying the error message, the Conjur follower would restart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We performed troubleshooting inside the Conjur Follower pod and verified that the follower could connect to the Conjur API leader successfully, but it was unable to connect to the Postgres database and complete the initial replication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur, authenticators and integrations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-authenticators-integrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 10:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-authenticators-integrations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the past few weeks, I have described what a secrets manager is and provided an overview of the architecture and system requirements of CyberArk Conjur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A secrets manager can&amp;rsquo;t do its job if it can&amp;rsquo;t communicate with those who need to request  secrets, and that&amp;rsquo;s where Conjur&amp;rsquo;s magic comes in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;authenticators&amp;rdquo; are responsible for the authentication process in Conjur and are specialized to do this in the most secure way, depending on the service.&lt;br&gt;
Here is the list of authenticators currently supported:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur: A Quick Overview of Architecture and System Requirements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-architecture-system-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 11:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cyberark-conjur-architecture-system-requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I wrote in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/why-you-need-kubernetes-secrets-manager/&#34;&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt;, CyberArk Conjur is an enterprise secrets manager.
, CyberArk Conjur is an enterprise secrets manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’ll provide an architecture overview along with the main system requirements.&lt;br&gt;
Conjur is currently available in two versions: Enterprise and open source (known as OSS).&lt;br&gt;
A &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; version will be available soon, offered as a SaaS solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post focuses on the Enterprise version, which is similar but not identical to the OSS version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberArk Conjur - why you (probably) need an enterprise secrets manager</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-you-need-kubernetes-secrets-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 16:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-you-need-kubernetes-secrets-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Security is always a complex topic to address, as an error or omission in processes can lead to serious economic or reputational damage for a company.&lt;br&gt;
When we talk about &amp;ldquo;secrets,&amp;rdquo; consider the following examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usernames&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database passwords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSL certificates and keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud credentials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply reading through this list helps to explain why this topic needs to be considered and handled carefully.&lt;br&gt;
Some common bad practices or risks include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
